Guide to the Clarence Prouty Shedd Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Clarence Prouty Shedd Papers
1915-1967
RG 35
Yale University Divinity School Library
36
(89 boxes)
The collection consists of correspondence, writings, and source material related almost entirely to Shedd's professional involvement in religious work among college and university students. Clarence Prouty Shedd received the B.A. degree in 1909 and the M.A. degree in 1914, both from Clark University, and earned a B.D. in 1925 and a Ph.D. in 1932 from Yale University. He taught in the fields of Christian methods and religion in higher education at Yale University from 1923 to 1955.
Shedd, Clarence Prouty, 1887-
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Biographical / Historical
1887 Born in Worcester, Mass.
1907-1926 Student Y.M.C.A. Secretary on the local, regional and national levels
1909 B.A., Clark University
1914 M.A., Clark University
1921 Traveled in Europe as member of commission making recommendations for European Student Relief
1923 Elected fellow of the National Council of Religion in Higher Education
1923-1925 Lecturer on Student Work, Yale University
1924-1926 Lecturer on Religious Education, Yale
1925 B.D., Yale
1926-1928 Assistant Professor of Christian Methods, on Stephen Merrell Clement Foundation, Yale
1928-1939 Associate Professor of Christian Methods, Yale
1930,1931 Dean of School for Student Y.M.C.A. Presidents held as part of the summer session at Union Theological Seminary. Shedd taught at various summer sessions throughout his career.
1931-1932 Sabbatical year in Europe, studying the Student Christian Movement in European universities
1932 Ph.D., Yale
1934-1935 Member of National Commission on Consultations about Student Christian Work
1939-1955 Stephen Merrell Clement Professor of Christian Methods, Yale
1941-1942, 1945-1947 Consultative trips to state universities in the U.S.
1948-1949 Sabbatical year in Switzerland doing research for a history of the World's Alliance of Y.M.C.A.'s
1951 L.H.D., Clark University
1955-1973 Professor Emeritus
1955, fall semester Visiting Lecturer in Religious Education and Psychology, Union Theological Seminary
1956-1959 Visiting Professor, Pacific School of Religion
1966 D.D., Pacific School of Religion
1973 Died
Scope and Contents
One folder of biographical material precedes Series I. The papers in this record group are almost entirely related to Shedd's professional involvement in religious work among college and university students. Shedd was both trailblazer and historian for the field of religion in higher education and his extensive files provide valuable documentary material.
The first series, Correspondence, dates from 1923 to 1967. Shedd maintained voluminous correspondence with many of the important figures in his field. Letters to and from David R. Porter, John R. Mott, Harold Colvin, Edwin Espy, Henry P. Van Dusen, and others provide insight into the policy development, important issues, trials, and successes of the Student Y.M.C.A. movement. As head of the Religion in Higher Education Program at Yale, Shedd was responsible for the training of many men and women who held influential positions directing student religious life on college and university campuses. Shedd was asked on many occasions to suggest candidates for open positions or to comment on possible selections. In the latter part of his career, Shedd was particularly interested in religious education programs at state universities and colleges. The progress of various programs and legal issues involved are discussed in Shedd's correspondence with university administrators and student work leaders. In some cases, the correspondence of an individual is included under the institution or organization that he or she represented. This is true, for example, in the case of universities Shedd corresponded with when making plans for his consultative trips. Information regarding the funding of Shedd's work is available under the headings: Alden, Clark, Hazen Foundation, Teagle, and in his file of correspondence with representatives of Yale University. All correspondence to and from representatives of Yale has been filed together because as a whole it provides an informative chronological sketch of Shedd's activities from 1925 to 1955.
It should be noted that not all of Shedd's correspondence is located in Series I. Shedd maintained a personal correspondence file and a source material file. The source material file was developed for the use of Shedd's students at Yale and for his personal use in documenting trends and issues in religion in higher education. The location of correspondence originally found in the source material file has not been changed. For instance, Shedd wrote to many universities requesting that they send printed material which would provide relevant information for his study of religion in state universities. Correspondence related to Shedd's obtaining this material remains in the source material file. To give another example, Shedd served as co-secretary of Commission VII of the National Student Faculty Conference in Detroit, 1930. Included with the drafts, revisions and final copy of the Commission's report in the source material file is correspondence regarding commission member selection, meeting times, etc. The majority of Shedd's substantive correspondence is in Series I, though a significant portion of the Series I correspondence also deals with technical matters such as arrangements for trips, obtaining funding, and scheduling meetings.
The second series, Writings, is divided into three subsections:
Addresses and Lectures
Articles
Book Reviews
All of the material in this series was written by Shedd. It covers the period from 1925 to 1966, thus providing insight into the development of Shedd's thought throughout his career.
The third series, Source Material, includes printed material, mimeographed reports, Shedd's notes on various subjects, reports and studies done by his students, completed questionnaires on various subjects, material related to the Religion in Higher Education program at Yale, etc. This series accounts for 67 of the 89 boxes in the collection. Shedd gathered source material on subjects ranging from women in higher education to the effects of World War II on religion in higher education to student summer conferences to fraternities to work among Negro students. Also included in this series is the material Shedd gathered while researching his three major publications: The Church Follows Its Students (published 1938), History of the World Alliance of Y.M.C.A.'s (1955), and Two Centuries of Student Christian Movements (1934).
An effort has been made to retain Shedd's organization of his source material files. Because of this, it is occasionally true that material on a particular topic can be found under two different headings. For example, material regarding summer conferences for students can be found under the heading "Student Summer Conferences" and under the heading " Two Centuries of Student Christian Movements - source material: Student Summer Conferences". In other cases it should be noted that material on a particular subject may be found under headings other than the most obvious heading. For example, a researcher concerned with the status of African Americans in student association work would find material of interest not only under the heading "Negroes" in the source material file, but also under the headings "National Student-Faculty Conference, Detroit 1930" and "Religion in Higher Education - Yale Program: Dissertation proposals, McKinney". Further relevant material would be found in Shedd's correspondence with representatives of the Y.M.C.A.
The source material file is voluminous and much of the material may be of limited significance. Scattered throughout, however, is primary source material and raw survey data which could be useful in tracing the history of religious work among college and university students.
Arrangement
I. Correspondence, 1923-1967
II. Writings, 1925-1966
III. Source Material, 1920s-1940s
Universities and colleges -- Religion; Young Men's Christian Associations; Educators; Espy, R. H. Edwin; Mott, John R. (John Raleigh), 1865-1955; Porter, David R. (David Richard), 1882-1973; Shedd, Clarence Prouty, 1887-; Van Dusen, Henry P. (Henry Pitney), 1897-1975; Edward W. Hazen Foundation; Yale University. Divinity School
- Correspondence, 1923-1967; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  The letters are arranged alphabetically by author or recipient other than Shedd. A general folder for each letter of the alphabet is followed by individual folders for notable correspondents. The few letters which are neither to nor from Shedd are filed by author. One folder of unidentified and fragmentary correspondence is located at the end of the series. One folder of biographical material precedes the correspondence.
  - Biographical Material, 1948-1955, 1966, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A, 1932-1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Adams, John Maxwell, 1940-1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alabama, University of, 1939-1962, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alaska, University of, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alden Trust Fund, 1950-1955, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Allen, Henry E., 1947-1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Council on Education, 1940-1947 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Arizona, University of, 1941-1956, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Arkansas, University of, 1946-1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - B, 1949-1955 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Baptist General Convention of Texas, 1950, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Blakeman, Edward W., 1937-1950, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Blanding, Sarah Gibson (see also: Vassar College), 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Blue Ridge Y.M.C.A. Conference Center, 1936-1940, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Bollinger, Hiel D., 1945-1951 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Bowling Green State University, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Brown, Forrest D., 1944-1953 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Brown University, 1946-1955 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Buffalo, University of, 1945, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - C, 1942-1954 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - California Institute of Technology, 1940-1961 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - California, University of (Berkeley), 1939-1963 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - California, University of (Los Angeles), 1940-1943 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - California, University of (Santa Barbara), 1964 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Campbell, E. Fay, 1928-1947, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Catawba College (North Carolina), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Cincinnati, University of, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - The Citadel (South Carolina), 1941, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - A. B. Clark Fund, 1942-1954, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Clement, Mrs. Stephen Merrell, 1927-1942, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Clemson Agricultural College, 1941, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Colorado State College, 1941, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Colorado, University of, 1931-1942 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Colorado Woman's College, 1950, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Columbia University, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Colvin, Harold W., 1938-1946 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Colvin, Harold W., 1946-1955, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Committee on Friendly Relations among Foreign Students, 1948-1951 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Connecticut, University of, 1942-1947 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Cornell University, 1941-1963 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Council of Student Christian Associations, 1928-1934, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Culver Military Academy, 1947, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - D, 1926-1950 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Danforth Foundation, 1939-1940 Aug (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Danforth Foundatlon, 1940 Sep-1942 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Danforth Foundation, 1943-1955, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Davidson College, 1944-1962 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Delaware, University of, 1941-1951 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - E, 1941, 1944, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - East Central Junior College (Mississippi), 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Eastern Michigan University, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Easton, William B., 1944-1947 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Eddy, G. Sherwood, 1943-1954 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Elliott, A. Roland, 1928-1936 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Elliott, A. Roland, 1937-1940 Jan (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Elliott, A. Roland, 1940 Feb-1941 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Elliott, A. Roland, 1942-1943, 1947, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Elon College (North Carolina), 1940 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Espy, R. H. Edwin, 1943-1944 Jan (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Espy, R. H. Edwin, 1944 Feb-1945 Mar (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Espy, R. H. Edwin, 1945 Apr-1946 Apr (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Espy, R. H. Edwin, 1946 May-1947 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Espy, R. H. Edwin, 1948-1952 Jul (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Espy, R. H. Edwin, 1952 Aug-1954, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Evansville College, 1947-1949 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - F, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Florida State University, 1955-1962, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Florida, University of, 1930-1962, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Fox, Lewis, 1942-1950, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Fresno State College, 1959-1961 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - G, 1938-1955 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - George Williams College (Chicago), 1940 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Georgia Institute of Technology, 1941, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Georgia, University of, 1945-1964 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Gilkey, Charles, 1947-1955 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - H, 1932-1955 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Harper and Brothers - Publishers, 1944, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Harvard University, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Edward W. Hazen Foundation, 1930-1931 Jan (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Edward W. Hazen Foundation, 1931 Feb-1938 (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - Edward W. Hazen Foundation, 1939-1941 (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - Edward W. Hazen Foundation, 1942-1944 (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Edward W. Hazen Foundation, 1945-1947 Jul (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Edward W. Hazen Foundation, 1947 Oct-1958, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - Houston, University of, 1955, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - Hunter College, 1944, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - Hyde, Albert Alexander, 1927-1932 (Box 7, Folder 88)
  - I, 1940-1945 (Box 7, Folder 89)
  - Illinois, University of, 1936-1961 (Box 7, Folder 90)
  - Indiana University, 1940, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 91)
  - Ingalls, Harold B., 1939-1954 (Box 7, Folder 92)
  - Iowa State College, 1940, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 93)
  - Iowa State Teachers College, 1940, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - lowa, University of, 1940-1952 (Box 8, Folder 95)
  - J, 1942-1954 (Box 8, Folder 96)
  - Johns Hopkins University, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 97)
  - K, 1944-1954 (Box 8, Folder 98)
  - Kansas State College, 1946-1951 (Box 8, Folder 99)
  - Kansas, University of, 1940-1944 (Box 8, Folder 100)
  - Kent State University, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 101)
  - Kentucky, University of, 1939-1941 (Box 8, Folder 102)
  - L, 1947-1964 (Box 8, Folder 103)
  - Lake Forest College, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 104)
  - Latourette, Kenneth Scott, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 105)
  - Limbert, Paul (see also: Y.M.C.A. - World's Alliance), 1944-1952 (Box 8, Folder 106)
  - Louisiana State University, 1939-1944 (Box 8, Folder 107)
  - Louisiana State University, 1945-1952, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 108)
  - Lovett, Sidney, 1945-1951 (Box 9, Folder 109)
  - M, 1934-1955 (Box 9, Folder 110)
  - Mackie, Robert C., 1944-1949 (Box 9, Folder 111)
  - Maine, University of, 1939-1946, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 112)
  - Maryland, University of, 1941-1951, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 113)
  - Massachusetts State College, 1940, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 114)
  - Maury, Philippe, 1949-1955, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 115)
  - Miami University (Ohio), 1941, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 116)
  - Michigan, University of, 1939-1959, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 117)
  - Miller, Francis P., 1927-1955 (Box 9, Folder 118)
  - Minnesota, University of, 1945-1951, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 119)
  - Mississippi State College for Women, 1960-1962 (Box 9, Folder 120)
  - Mississippi, University of Mississippi State University, 1939-1961 (Box 9, Folder 121)
  - Missouri, University of, 1940-1947, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 122)
  - Montana State University, 1941-1955 (Box 9, Folder 123)
  - Morehouse College, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 124)
  - Mott, John R. (and his secretaries), 1925-1955 (Box 9, Folder 125)
  - N, 1944-1952 (Box 10, Folder 126)
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews, Inc., 1943-1955 (Box 10, Folder 127)
  - National Council of Churches of Christ in the U.S.A., 1951-1952 (Box 10, Folder 128)
  - National Council on Religion in Higher Education, 1938-1955 (Box 10, Folder 129)
  - Nebraska, University of, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 130)
  - New Mexico State College, 1940-1941 (Box 10, Folder 131)
  - New Mexico, University of, 1942, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 132)
  - North Carolina State College, 1949-1963, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 133)
  - North Carolina, University of, 1940-1960 (Box 10, Folder 134)
  - North Carolina, University of (Woman's College), 1940-1951 (Box 10, Folder 135)
  - Northwestern University, 1940-1962, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 136)
  - O (Box 10, Folder 137)
  - Oberlin College, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 138)
  - Ohio State University, 1939-1967 (Box 10, Folder 139)
  - Ohio University, 1941, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 140)
  - Oklahoma Agricultural and Mechanical College, 1940-1946 (Box 10, Folder 141)
  - Oklahoma College for Women, 1941, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 142)
  - Oklahoma, University of, 1940-1942 (Box 11, Folder 143)
  - Oregon State College, 1940-1951, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 144)
  - Oregon, University of, 1939-1944 (Box 11, Folder 145)
  - P, 1946-1951, 1962, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 146)
  - Pacific School of Religion, 1947, 1956-1965 (Box 11, Folder 147)
  - Pennsylvania State University, 1931-1960, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 148)
  - Pennsylvania University of, 1939-1945, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 149)
  - Pittsburgh, University of, 1945-1947 (Box 11, Folder 150)
  - Porter, David R. (see also: Y.M.C.A.: New Student Committee and Student Christian Movement in New England), 1927-1952 (Box 11, Folder 151)
  - Porter, David R., 1933-1954, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 152)
  - Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A., 1951, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 153)
  - Princeton University, 1945-1947 (Box 12, Folder 154)
  - Protestant Episcopal Church, 1948-1952 (Box 12, Folder 155)
  - R, 1936-1947 (Box 12, Folder 156)
  - Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 157)
  - Rhode Island State College, 1941, 1942 (Box 12, Folder 158)
  - Ronald Press Company, 1944-1949 Apr (Box 12, Folder 159)
  - Ronald Press Company, 1949 May-1951 Feb (Box 12, Folder 160)
  - Ronald Press Company, 1951 Mar-1952 (Box 12, Folder 161)
  - Ronald Press Company, 1953-1963 (Box 12, Folder 162)
  - Rouse, Ruth, 1939-1954 (Box 12, Folder 163)
  - Rutgers University, 1941-1955 (Box 12, Folder 164)
  - S, 1944-1954 (Box 12, Folder 165)
  - Sam Houston State Teachers College, 1941, 1942 (Box 12, Folder 166)
  - San Diego State College, 1957-1963 (Box 12, Folder 167)
  - Smith College, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 168)
  - Smith, Seymour A., 1951-1952 (Box 13, Folder 169)
  - Smith, Seymour A., 1953-1956, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 170)
  - South Carolina, University of, 1939-1962, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 171)
  - South Dakota State College, 1941, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 172)
  - South Dakota, University of, 1941, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 173)
  - South Florida, University of, 1962, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 174)
  - Southern California, University of, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 175)
  - Southern Methodist University, 1954-1956 (Box 13, Folder 176)
  - Southwest Missouri State College, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 177)
  - Spelman College, 1960, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 178)
  - Stanford University, 1943-1951, 1963, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 179)
  - Stewart, George (see also: Source Material - Y.M.C.A. - Committee of Four ), 1927-1938 (Box 13, Folder 180)
  - Stewart, George, 1939-1946, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 181)
  - Strong, Tracy, 1947-1950 Aug (Box 13, Folder 182)
  - Strong, Tracy, 1950 Sep-1954, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 183)
  - Student Christian Movement in New England (includes some material from Y.M.C.A. New England Student Committee, from transition years 1934, 1935), 1934-1952 (Box 14, Folder 184)
  - Student Christian Movement of Great Britain and Ireland, 1945-1955 (Box 14, Folder 185)
  - Student Christian Movement of the Middle Atlantic Region, 1929-1952 (Box 14, Folder 186)
  - Student Volunteer Movement, 1937-1950 (Box 14, Folder 187)
  - T, 1942-1954 (Box 14, Folder 188)
  - Talladega College, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 189)
  - Teagle Foundation, 1945-1949 (Box 14, Folder 190)
  - Teagle Foundation, 1950-1955, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 191)
  - Tennessee Polytechnic Institute, 1942 (Box 14, Folder 192)
  - Tennessee, University of, 1940-1947 (Box 14, Folder 193)
  - Texas Christian University, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 194)
  - Texas, University of, 1939-1955, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 195)
  - Tucker, Luther, 1940-1949, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 196)
  - U, 1945-1954 (Box 14, Folder 197)
  - Union College, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 198)
  - Union Theological Seminary (see also: SOURCE MATERIAL - Summer Courses for Leaders of University Religious Work), 1948-1955 (Box 15, Folder 199)
  - United States Army, 1946-1948 (Box 15, Folder 200)
  - United Student Christian Council, 1945-1954, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 201)
  - University Christian Mission, 1946-1954, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 202)
  - Uphaus, Willard, 1931 (Box 15, Folder 203)
  - Utah, University of, 1940-1946, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 204)
  - V, 1948-1954 (Box 15, Folder 205)
  - Van Dusen, Henry P., 1938-1952 (Box 15, Folder 206)
  - Vassar College (see also: Blanding, S.G.), 1941-1950 (Box 15, Folder 207)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute, 1938-1962 (Box 15, Folder 208)
  - Virginia Union University, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 209)
  - Virginia, University of, 1940-1961 (Box 15, Folder 210)
  - Visser 't Hooft, W.A., 1933-1954 (Box 15, Folder 211)
  - W, 1945-1962 (Box 15, Folder 212)
  - Wabash College, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 213)
  - Washington and Lee University, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 214)
  - Washington State College, 1939-1949, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 215)
  - Washington University, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 216)
  - Washington, University of, 1939-1942, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 217)
  - West Virginia University, 1941-1951 (Box 16, Folder 218)
  - Wingate College, 1960, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 219)
  - Winthrop College, 1940-1946 (Box 16, Folder 220)
  - Wisconsin, University of, 1939-1947 (Box 16, Folder 221)
  - Wright, Elizabeth, 1947-1953 (Box 16, Folder 222)
  - Wright, Henry B., 1923, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 223)
  - Y, 1940-1947 (Box 16, Folder 22L)
  - Yale Divinity School Library, 1945- 1967, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 225)
  - Yale University, 1925-1929 (Box 16, Folder 226)
  - Yale University, 1930-1931 (Box 16, Folder 227)
  - Yale University, 1932-1937 Mar (Box 16, Folder 228)
  - Yale University, 1937 May-1941 (Box 16, Folder 229)
  - Yale University, 1942-1947 (Box 16, Folder 230)
  - Yale University, 1948-1949 Apr (Box 17, Folder 231)
  - Yale University, 1949 May-1950 (Box 17, Folder 232)
  - Yale University, 1951 Jan-1953 Apr (Box 17, Folder 233)
  - Yale University, 1953 May-1955 (Box 17, Folder 23L)
  - Yale University, 1956-1959, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 235)
  - Yale University Press, 1944-1948 (Box 17, Folder 236)
  - Y.M.C.A. - Central Field, 1930-1955 (Box 17, Folder 237)
  - Y.M.C.A. - International Committee, 1937-1948 (Box 17, Folder 238)
  - Y.M.C.A. - National Council (see also: A.R. Elliott), 1927-1955 (Box 17, Folder 239)
  - Y.M.C.A. - National Student Council, 1954-1962 (Box 18, Folder 240)
  - Y.M.C.A. - Pacific Southwest and Northwest - Area Councils, 1929, 1950-1963 (Box 18, Folder 241)
  - Y.M.C.A. - Rocky Mountain Field, 1929-1939, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 242)
  - Y.M.C.A. - Southern Area Council, 1929-1962, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 243)
  - Y.M.C.A. - Southwest Council, 1933-1952, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 244)
  - Y.M.C.A. - World's Alliance of Y.M.C.A.'s (see also: Tracy Strong), 1948-1955 (Box 18, Folder 245)
  - Y.M.C.A. of New Haven, 1930-1963 (Box 18, Folder 246)